Annette Lee | UX / UI DESIGNER

Shoreline, WA | 1-(425) 480-1276 | AnnetteLee.2018@gmail.com | https://eigoganbare.com

Professional Summary:

More than 5+ years of voluntarily UX design experience in user interface design system of 200+ viewers accessing my Eigo Ganbare website on a daily basis. Ability to incorporate educational classroom technology, such as designing e-learning and game-based learning platforms, as well as applying an immersive learning experience with AR apps. Specialize in providing and developing a team-teaching resource website to be used nationwide in Japanese schools. Acted as cross-cultural ambassador and a native English-speaking teacher in Japan.

Core Skills:

- User Experience
- Prototype Design
- Usability Design
- Storyboarding
- User Interface Design
- HTML/JS/CSS

- Final Cut Pro X
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Digital Transformation
- Cross-cultural experience
- Lessons Curriculum Development
- Classroom Technological Integration

UX Design - Work Experience

Web Content Creator — Eigo Ganbare, Japan/USA

04/2010 - Present

- Create a self-initiated project of a team-teaching resource website that was designed entirely with WordPress, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, and Adobe Creative Suite.
- Use Scrum and Agile methodologies to develop classroom materials.
- Apply design solutions with visual interactive, gaming, and augmented reality features.
- Create online web-based activities and accessibility support to facilitate student learning, utilizing H5P and user-centered gamification architecture.
- Design clickable wireframes of the teacher and classroom portal which included a built-in Nextcloud platform to enhance the user desktop and mobile experience.

UX Design & TechEdu Research Experience

Native English Teacher (NET) — Osaka Seiryo JHS & Senior High School

04/2018 - 03/2020

- Collaborated with 4-5 Japanese teachers of English to engage JHS and HS students' interest in English and foreign cultures, as well team-hosted the annual English speech contests.
- Experienced in applying iterative web based design process with KeyNote and PowerPoint and utilized other online design tools to support student engagement.
- Engaged students to think creatively and critically in teams while utilizing their iPad for brainstorming, creating mockups, and doing group research projects.
- Implemented a pen pal letter exchange program in 7 high school English classes and 2 junior high school English classes while serving as a liaison with Japanese language classes in the United States.

- Collaborated with 30+ JHS and ES Japanese teachers of English to assist them with the implementation of major English education and classroom technological reforms.
- Developed problem-solving, visual design interface, and deep-learning usability principles into students' worksheets.
- Integrated AR technologies, educational web app technologies, user-friendly design quizzes, and foreign cultures. Devised a responsive mockup strategy to increase ES students' English communication skills.
- Implemented a pen pal letter exchange program with in 12 junior high school English classes.
- Developed a portfolio to optimize the Pen Pal Project to increase international outreach and scope of the program.
- Assisted with hosting and facilitating an official international event ceremony of students from Guam, televised on a Japanese news broadcast.

Native English Teacher (NET) — Hirakata City Board of Education

04/2012 - 07/2015

- Established a pen pal letter exchange project which involved 16 junior high school classes with Japanese language classes in the US and included a LIVE video chat conference.
- Experienced with motion design and video creation to create green screen visual effects, special effects, and video animation effects.
- Incorporated Final Cut Pro X and Adobe After Effects for extensive video editing on students' public speaking presentations.
- Revitalized graph design illustrations of the second-year JHS school trip to Uji city, Kyoto.

Other Teaching Experience

Assistant English Teacher (AET) — City Staff Co., LTD / Ivy Co., LTD/ Interac Co., LTD

Takatsuki City Board of Education 04/2009 - 01/2012

Kakogawa City Board of Education 09/2005 - 03/2006, 04/2007 - 03/2009

Tech Industry Work Experience

Sales/Marketing — Pacific Software Publishing, Bellevue, WA, USA

09/2006 - 03/2007

- Met with Japanese and American clients to discuss web & email hosting services.
- Documented preparation such as proposals, estimates, and contracts.

Education

FreeCodeCamp — Certifications: Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures

University of Washington — Dual Bachelors of Arts in Sociology & Linguistics

UW Japanese Technical Program | Hyogo Business & Cultural Center — Web design Intern at Sohatsu Systems Inc., Kobe

Japan Exchange Teaching Program — (Kasai city BOE) Assistant Language Teacher